准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
时光胶囊
感谢各位莅临今天的时光胶囊典礼
Thank you for attending today's time capsule ceremony
非常有必要让未来一代了解
It's important that future generations know
让裤头村出众的特点
what made Bikini Bottom special
以及裤头村居民与其任意的个人物品
its citizens and their random personal belongings
现在  请欢迎珊迪奇克斯小姐
And now, please welcome Miss Sandy Cheeks
感谢市长小姐
Thank you, Miss Mayor
我设计了这个金属容器
I designed this metallic vessel
可以完美保存里面的东西
to perfectly preserve anything inside
不过有一个特定的时限
for a very specific amount of time
时限多少呢  珊迪
How much time, Sandy?
不知道  大约两千年左右吧
I don't know, like, 2,000-ish years
典礼开始吧
Let the ceremony begin
我只想留一条快乐好消息
I just want to leave a happy message
为明天的居民们听
for the good people of tomorrow
好高档的垃圾桶
What a fancy trash can
你拿我竖笛干什么
What are you doing with my clarinet?
让它变成未来的问题
Making it the future's problem
让开  章鱼哥先生
Out of my way, Mr. Squidward
未来的客人肯定会出高价
Customers of the future will pay top dollar
买个陈年原版蟹黄堡
for a vintage original Krabby Patty
能现在直接收钱吗  还是要再等等
Can I charge for this now or do I have to wait?
本次重要典礼到此结束
And that concludes this momentous occasion
感谢大家来
Thank you all so much for--
别急着走啊
Not so fast
你们这群白痴
You fools
有蟹黄堡在手
With this patty in my grasp
我终于能统治世界了
I can finally take over the world
好  以后再说
Yeah, maybe later
两千年
2,000 years
很久以后再说
Much later
放我出去
Let me out of here
我得把你们都消灭了
I have to destroy you all
不要
No
海神王啊  不要
Neptune, no
我刚说到  感谢大家莅临
As I was saying, thanks for coming, everybody
市政厅送免费匹萨
Free pizza at city hall
免费
Free
匹萨  匹萨
Pizza, pizza
这次又惹上什么麻烦了  谢尔顿
What have you gotten yourself into this time, Sheldon?
凯伦  快给我开罐器什么的
Karen, get me a can opener or something, quick
看来只能等它自己打开了
Well, guess we have to wait until it opens up
来日再见吧
I'll see you later
两千年左右之后
终于啊
At last
靠每顿一个蟹黄堡分子维持生命体征
after surviving on this patty one molecule at a time
总算破解秘密配方了
I've finally cracked the secret formula
我的恐怖统治终于能
Now my reign of terror can be--
等一下
wait a minute
这垃圾堆看着没那么垃圾了
This dump looks less dumpy
未来一定很棒
The future must be pretty great
毕竟一切都是铬做的  还挺滑的
if everything's made of chrome, and slidey
漂亮
Pretty
铬之霸
什么
What?
铬之霸
The Chrome Bucket?
门哪去了
Where's the door?
进不去实验室还怎么统治世界
I can't take over the world if I can't even get into my lab
凯伦  放我进去
Karen, let me in
谢尔顿  欢迎回家
Sheldon, welcome home
凯伦  是你吗
Karen, is that you?
你好像整容了
I see you've had some work done
我整的东西多着呢
And that's not the only work I've been doing
你完成了某种致命毁灭机器人吗
Have you completed
some kind of deadly destructive robot?
没有
Negative
我在做艺术品
I have been working on my art pieces
其实还挺成功
I'm quite successful, in fact
亲爱的  这东西很配客厅沙发
Honey, this would match the couch in the living room
我们买了
We'll take it
谁稀罕什么艺术
Who cares about art?
来帮我统治世界
Time to help me take over the world
大门怎么了
Now, what happened to the front door?
不管了
Never mind
你不明白  痞老板
You don't understand, Plankton
天下已经大变了
The whole world is different now
等等  你什么意思
Wait, what do you mean?
我给你看看
Let me show you
看吧
See?
章鱼哥博物馆
这是章鱼哥的老房子
This is Squidward's old house
章鱼哥博物馆
Museum of Squidward?
谁会去参观纪念那废物的博物馆
Who would ever go to a museum dedicated to that loser?
来参观的有不少呢
Lots of people
章鱼哥以前的竖笛录音
Squidward's old clarinet recordings
现在是公认的古典乐了
are considered classical music now
以前大伙完全不把它当音乐的
They weren't considered music at all before
可惜他逝世后  作品才得到大众欣赏
Sadly, no one started listening to them
until the day after he was gone
果不其然
Typical
派大星的石头现在长这样
This is what Patrick's rock looks like now
那笨蛋向来是个白痴
That moron was always an idiot
他的破汽水杯
And his stupid soda cup
害我两千年都黏糊糊的
left me sticky for 2,000 years
要是他在这里
If he were here right now
我就给他松弛的下巴来一记
I'd sock him right in his slack jaw
这位是派一千
And this is the P-1000
我饿了
I'm hungry
我要吃铬金属点心
I need a chrome snack
就算他变机器人了也是白痴
Even as a robot he's an idiot
吃的
Food
味道不像是铬
This doesn't taste like chrome
我要继续睡了
I'm going back to bed
我猜猜看
Now, let me guess--
你接下来要给我看海绵宝宝怎么了
next, you're going to show me what happened to SpongeBob
本来没这打算  但你要看就看
I wasn't, but if you insist
酷哥酷姐
Hey, cats
近来如何
How's it hanging?
感谢顺道过来  懂不
Thanks for stopping by, ya dig?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
这里居然会有东西真的改善了
I can't believe something here has actually improved
而且那东西就是你
and that something was you
那不是海绵宝宝
It's not SpongeBob
是他的全息门卫
It's his holographic doorman
这才是真正的海绵宝宝
This is the real SpongeBob
至少是他的残余物
or at least what's left of him
他喜欢你
He likes you
快让它住口
Make it stop
那笑声的回声已经困扰我两千年了
I was haunted by the echoes of that laugh for 2,000 years
我懂了
OK, I get it
未来很糟糕
The future is awful
但我现在知道秘密配方了
But I know the secret formula now
我们能统治这个垃圾时间线了
We can take over this horrible timeline
秘方的事
About that
似乎还有一点东西得让你看看
I think there's something else you should see
铬堡王
The Kromey Krab?
因生锈永久停业
"Permanently closed due to rust"
真是好消息
This is great news
不见得
Not exactly
蟹堡王营不营业都无所谓了
It doesn't matter if the Krusty Krab is open or not
未来居民全都知道秘密配方
In the future, everyone knows the secret formula
他们什么
They what?
不要
No
够了
That's it
我受够未来了
I've had it with the future
我只想回到我恨的那些臭鱼烂虾身边
I just want to go back to all the people I hate
怎么不早说呢
Why didn't you say so?
我认识可能会帮得上忙的某位
I know someone who might be able to help
那个怪松鼠
The screwy squirrel?
不会吧
Really?
反正那松鼠也没被困在管子里
The squirrel didn't get trapped in a tube
整整两千年  对吧
for 2,000 years, did she?
好像有点道理
Touché, I guess
太诡异了
This is weird
珊迪家样子完全没变
Sandy's place looks exactly the same
没错  但是注意
Indeed, but be warned
珊迪可能与你记忆中的样子不太一样
Sandy may not be exactly how you remember her
谁这么大胆  敢敲我树屋的门
Who dares to knock upon my dome?
你好
Hello?
珊迪
Sandy?
你在吗
Are you in there?
嗨
Hi!
珊迪·奇克斯听候差遣  痞老板
Sandy Cheeks at your service, Mr. Plankton.
什么
What the--
你怎么变年轻的
how did you get younger?
我一直都在穿越时空
I've just been jumping through the ages
自从珊瑚营地夏令营结束后就这样了
since summer ended at Kamp Koral.
所以是在探索时空是吧
Just exploring space and time, huh?
太厉害了
How wonderful
求你带我回到现代吧
Please take me back to the present, please
我讨厌未来
I hate the future
太讨厌了
I hate it
不用求我  痞老板
No need to beg, Mr. Plankton.
我就等着你呢
I've been expecting you.
时光机的燃料已经充满了
The time hopper's all gassed up.
那时光机在哪
Well, where is it?
你站的地方就是时光机啊
You're standing in it, partner.
这座树屋就是我的反向时光胶囊
This here tree dome is my reverse time capsule.
那还等什么呢
Then what are we waiting for?
出发吧
Away we go
再见了  凯伦
So long, Karen
两千年前见
See you 2,000 years ago
你可以出来了  痞老板二点零
You can come out now, Plankton 2.0
还以为他要赖在这了
I thought he'd never leave
往我身上涂点铬吧  宝贝
Now lay some chrome on me, baby
海之霸
没想到我会这么说
I never thought I'd say this
我太想念这个烂地方了
but I missed this horrible place
多谢你帮忙什么的
And thank you for your help or whatever
快走开
Be gone now
你是不是忘了什么事
Ain't you forgetting something?
好好好
All right, all right
一块钱找得开吗
Can you break a single?
不用给小费
I don't need a tip
但得让你忘掉秘密配方
but I will need you to forget that secret formula.
别动  我要启动我的记忆消除装置了
Hold still while I activate my memory-erasing device.
你的什么
Your what?
夏令营再见  痞老板
See you back at camp, Mr. Plankton.
怎么回事
What happened?
我怎么会到这来
How did I get here?
未来的客人肯定会出高价
Customers of the future will pay top dollar
买个陈年原版蟹黄堡
for a vintage original Krabby Patty
蟹黄堡
A Krabby Patty
机会来了
Now's my chance
别急着走啊
Not so fast
你们这群白痴
You fools
谁有似曾相识的感觉
Is anyone else having déjà vu?
两千年左右再见  痞老板
See you in 2,000-ish years, Plankton
两千年
2,000 years
深仇大恨
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
小蜗
Oh, Gary
早餐做好了
Breakfast is served
小蜗
Gary?
你今早声音不一样了
You sure sound different this morning
原来是娜琳的海骡子
It's Narlene's sea mule
你好啊  兄弟
Hey there, buddy
你是来看我的吗
Did you come to see me?
播放我
"Play me"
派大星  珊迪
Patrick, Sandy
你
you--
我会诺比语
I speak Nobbese
这就帮你翻译
I'll translate for you
娜琳和诺比邀请你
Narlene and Nobby invite you
派大星  珊迪
Patrick, Sandy
而且绝对没请章鱼哥
and definitely not Squidward
过来参加家族年度黄蜂水母酱大丰收
to our family's Annual Bumble Jelly Harvest
地点在裤头呼喊谷
in Bikini Holler
这则录音自爆倒计时  三
This recording will self-destruct in three
二
two
一
one
零
ze--
乖一点  小蜗
Be a good boy, Gary
我马上回来
I'll be back later
我们上路要前往裤头呼喊谷
Oh, we're on our way to Bikini Holler
在身后的道路缩得越来越小
The road behind us is getting smaller
绿草青青
The grass is green
树木变得高高
And the trees are taller
送一块钱  我就不会再唱下去
And I'll stop yodeling for just a dollar
干嘛要停下来
Why in tarnation are we stopping?
快点啊  骡子
Come on, mule
动起来
Get moving
下面的小心
Look out below
娜琳
Narlene
诺比
Nobby
就是本人
In the flesh
本人
Flesh
你们好啊  娜琳跟诺比
Howdy, Narlene and Nobby
你们的骡子好像完全不动了
Seems your mule just plum stopped moving
要不然打开它  看看引擎怎么样了
Why don't I open her up and check the engine?
你长脑袋是干什么用的
Why do you even have a head, huh?
这样雨水不会流进脖子上的洞
It keeps the rain out of my neck hole
上来
Get in
怎么了
What gives?
之所以骡子不愿意走这里
The mule refuses to walk through these parts
是因为这段路会经过
'cause this here road goes right through--
浮游生物领地
Plankton Territory?
没错  浮游生物
That's right, Planktons
独角鲸禁止入内
"Narwhals keep out"?
给我回去  独角鲸
Go home, Narwhals
这里是浮游生物的地盘
This here is Plankton land
你们休想伸着花哨长牙来这里
We don't want your fancy ivory tusks around here
快逃啊
Let's skedaddle
他们为什么这样
Why are they doing this?
浮游生物和独角鲸
Planktons and the Narwhals
是好几代的世仇
have been feuding for generations
他们宣称黄蜂水母田是他们自己的
They claim the bumble jelly fields are theirs
可那明明是我们的才对
while we know they're ours
为什么不共享水母田
Why don't you share the fields?
那有什么好玩的
Well, where's the fun in that?
我们到了  黄蜂水母田
Here we be, bumble jelly fields
我的兄弟在那用角戳树
My brothers there peck the trees
黄蜂水母就在树里储存水母酱
where the bumble jellies store their jelly
我的姐妹在那边
My sisters over there
则喜欢从蜂巢现挤
like to squeeze it fresh right out of the hive
长辈则更愿意吹小夜曲
The old folks prefer to serenade
让水母直接出水母酱
the jelly out of the bumbles
海绵宝宝  珊迪
SpongeBob, Sandy
见见我们爸妈
meet our ma and pa
你们好
Howdy
那个粉红城市佬是跟你们一起的吗
Say, man, is that pink city slicker with you?
他真勇敢
He sure is brave
勇敢
Brave?
对
Yup
之所以黄蜂水母
The only reason the bumble jellies
愿意让我们采集水母酱
let us collect their jelly
就只因为我们同意被它们蜇
is because we allow 'em to sting us
你们得被它们蜇
You let them sting you?
没错
Darn tootin'
我赞成
I consent
太值得了
It's worth it
救命
Help
没事  小子
There, there, son
你不要乱动  才能完成
You gotta hold still to complete the, uh
社会契约
social contract
问题不大  对吧
Well, now that wasn't so bad now, was it?
没错
No, sir
黄蜂水母
Bumble jelly
我宣布  今年黄蜂水母酱大丰收
I declare that this here
is a bountiful bumper crop of beautiful bumble jelly
收成时间结束了
Harvest time is over
黄蜂水母节开始吧
Let the bumble jelly festival commence
水母节
Festival
水母坐
Jelly flop
轮廓不错
Good contour
结构强劲
Strong structure
风格很大胆
A very bold mold
你们怎么有个穿大衣的表亲
Why is your cousin in the long trench coat
在打翻那个装水母酱的桶
tipping over that jelly barrel?
等一下
Wait a sec
那不是表亲
That ain't no cousin
是浮游生物
It's Planktons
浮游生物
Planktons
让他们尝尝厉害
Let 'em have it
世仇来了
We've got ourselves a feud
海神王啊
Lordy Neptune
我中土豆弹了
I've been spud smacked
准备开火
Fire in the hole
好耶
Yeah
现在怎么办
What do we do now?
他们浮游生物
Them Planktons
就算能拿海底所有土豆扔我们
can throw all the potatoes in the ocean at us
我们还是有一样特别的东西
We've got us something special
能帮我们取得决定性胜利
that'll give us a decisive victory
秘密武器
Secret weapon
还要更多土豆
We need more taters
不好了
Oh, no
大家找掩护
Everyone take cover
是鞋子
It's shoes
倒霉透了
Well, this stinks
不好了
Oh, no
我没鞋子了
I'm out of shoes
已经全都扔过去了
We plum tossed 'em all
那什么声音
What's that sound?
我不怎么知道
I don't rightly know
听着像是鞋子
Sounds like shoes
我们要求休战
We'd like a truce
独角鲸和浮游生物没有理由
Ain't no reason Narwhals and Plankton
不能共享水母田
can't share the fields
更何况我们已经没弹药了
Besides, we ran out of ammo
都怪你们家爱吃土豆的城市佬
thanks to your tater-eating city slicker
干得漂亮  派大星
Nice work, Patrick
尽职尽责是我的责任
It was an honor to serve
休战是吧
A truce, eh?
反正我们也没鞋子了
Well, seeing as how we're all out of shoes
你们想要回去吗
You want 'em back?
没事
Oh, heck
你们留着吧
You can keep 'em
此外我们也没觉得鞋子有什么用
Besides, we ain't found much use for 'em
现在又怎么了
What happens now?
一年一度仇后派对
The annual post-feud party
一年一度
Annual?
你们是说每年都这样吗
You mean you do this every year?
没错
Sure do
很好玩啊
It's fun
你们玩得不痛快吗
Why, didn't y'all have fun?
我们并没有玩得痛快
We did not have fun
我们过了
We had
最美好的一天
The best day ever
黄蜂水母
Bumble jelly